Ratnadeep Bhattacharya

800 22nd St NW, Room 400 Washington DC 20052

Email: ratnadeep.bhattacharya1983@gmail.com Web: https://ratnadeepb.github.io/

I am Ratnadeep Bhattacharya, a PhD student in the Department of Computer Science, <u>George Washington University</u>. I am part of the <u>Cloud Systems Lab</u> and my advisor is <u>Prof. Timothy Wood</u>. I have extensive experience in the industry designing and building data centers

Education

George Washington University

PhD, Computer Science Advisor: Dr. Timothy Wood August 2018 – May 2023 (Expected)

West Bengal University of Technology

Bachelor of Technology, Electrical Engineering - 7.41/10

National Merit Scholarship, 2000 – 2002, Government of India

Research Interests

- Network Function Virtualization (NFV), Edge Computing, Data Center/Cloud Networks and Systems
- Using Machine Learning and Queuing Theory for dynamic resource management

Research Experience

- Multi-Query Scalable Isomorphic Subgraph Matching in Large Graphs, January 2019 present
- Applying Machine Learning to classify resource usage by NFV applications, January 2019
 present
- Using Classification to identify SLA compliance of applications hosted on virtual machines, 2014, Bank Muscat, Muscat, Oman

Skills and Attributes

- Comfortable programming with Python, C and Bash. Familiar with Java
- Working knowledge of Linux and Unix variants
- Working knowledge of machine learning and the scikit-learn library.
- Familiar with the Ryu SDN controller and OpenFlow 1.3 standard
- Familiar with NFV and DPDK

Certifications

- VMware Certified Professional (VCP3, VCP4, VCP5) Data Center Virtualization (all now expired)
- Oracle Certified Associate, Solaris 11 System Administration

Work History

- George Washington University August 2018 till present
 - Currently working as a Research Assistant for Dr. Timothy Wood
- **IMTAC LLC** June 2012 to July 2018
 - o Analyze business needs of customers and translate the same to technical design.
 - Support clients to set up disaster resistant infrastructure using products from multiple vendors.
- IBM India February 2011 to June 2012
 - Maintaining the virtual infrastructure of a major commercial bank in USA.
 - Mentoring team members on VMware related technology.
- KPIT Cummins May 2009 to February 2011
 - KPIT Cummins was VMware Inc's support partner in India between 2009 and 2011. I was recruited to provide support to the North American customers of VMware Inc on VMware's range of product.
 - Mentor and lead a team of 6 engineers.
 - Recruit new engineers and deliver part of their training program.
 - Write knowledge base articles as and when required
- **HP Globalsoft** January 2009 to May 2009
 - Provide support for HP customers on HP Proliant servers and HP MSA storage.
- **HP** September 2008 to December 2008
 - Provide field support to HP customers.
- Keane India July 2009 to July 2008
 - o Provide support to Unisys and IBM mainframes. Also support windows and Linux servers. All in the internal data center.
 - Provide support to internal users.

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant, Operating Systems, Fall 2018